www.bks.name
sigurdson.brian@gmail.com
https://github.com/brian-sigurdson
www.linkedin.com/in/brian-sigurdson-985b5a159

Brian Sigurdson

SUMMARY

I enjoy working at the intersection of different areas of technology, such as: cloud computing, software engineering, databases, Big Data, Linux, and DevOps. Through coursework and projects, I have gained experience programming in Python, Java, and C++; using and administering relational databases such as MySQL and PostgreSQL, working with Big Data technologies such as Hadoop, and interacting with cloud computing through Amazon Web Services.

EDUCATION

Bowling Green State University	Master of Science	Computer Science	3.3/4.0	2018-08-04
Bowling Green State University	Master of Arts	Statistics	3.2/4.0	2016-08-06
The University of Toledo	BBA	Accounting	3.0/4.0	1994-08-06

RELEVANT CURRENT AND IN-PROGRESS CERTIFICATIONS

* Java SE 7 Programmer - Professional	Exam 2018-12-20	* Red Hat Certified System Administrator	Passed 2018
* Java SE 7 Programmer – Associate	Passed 2018	* AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate	Passed 2018
* Sun Certified Java Programmer (1.4)	Passed 2004	* AWS Certified Developer - Associate	Passed 2018
* Sun Certified Java Programmer (1.2)	Passed 2001	* AWS Certified SysOps Admin Associate	Passed 2018
* Sun Certified Web Component Dev. (1.3)	Passed 2004	* OCP, MySQL 5.6 Developer	Passed 2018
* Sun Certified Web Component Dev. (1.2)	Passed 2002	* OCP, MySQL 5.6 Database Administrator	Passed 2018
* Sun Certified Business Component Dev.	Passed 2004	* Oracle9i DBA Certified Associate	Passed 2006

RELEVANT PROJECTS

BGSU Master's Project Extension: Automated Amazon Web Services Deployment (current development)

- The application is a Java Swing GUI designed to allow the user to deploy a Boa cluster as described below, but to deploy on AWS instead of CloudLab.
- Technologies used:
 - Java, Swing GUI, Eclipse/NetBeans, AWS SDK for Java, and Git/GitHub
- Results:
 - After the user indicates their preferences for the cluster's key architectural items, such as region, instance size, and the number of managed nodes; the application will interact with AWS and create a virtual private cloud in the user's account, hosting the new cluster.
 - Within 20 minutes the user can interact with a dynamically created, N-node Boa cluster running Hadoop, by using their web browser.
- Project Code: https://github.com/brian-sigurdson/boa-aws-java-swing-deployment

BGSU Master's Project: Automated CloudLab Deployment (2017-2018)

- Automated deployment of an N-node dynamically sized Boa cluster using Hadoop and running on CloudLab (a private cloud service).
- Technologies used:

- Ubuntu, Ansible, Bash, CloudLab, Apache HTTP Server, Drupal, MySQL, VS Code, and Git/GitHub
- Results:
 - A reduction in time and complexity to deploy a Boa cluster on CloudLab from hours or days to approximately 20 minutes.
 - Upon completion of the deployment process, the user has a functional Boa cluster using Hadoop, running in a private cloud, using Ubuntu, Apache HTTP Server, and MySQL, with a Drupal user interface.

Project Paper: http://bks.name/projects/bgsu-masters/boidae-personal-mining.pdf

Project Code: https://github.com/brian-sigurdson/boa-ansible-bash-hadoop

Project Poster: http://bks.name/projects/bgsu-masters/Poster-Boa-Cloudlab.png

Project Video: https://boa.page.link/BoidaeFSE18

Oldcastle Perrysburg: Accounting Department Website (2001-2006)

- On my own initiative, I learned the necessary tools and technologies to develop a department website that streamlined the month-end closing cycle.
- Technologies used:
 - Java, Postgresql, MySQL, Tomcat, Jboss, JEE/J2EE, JSP/Servlets, HTML, Networking, Linux, Apache POI, and Eclipse
- Results:
 - Automated repetitive and error prone tasks, saving hours of processing time during each monthend close cycle.
 - Extracted journal entry information directly from Excel spreadsheets and uploaded it to the AS/400 for posting.
 - Reduced the time required to create the Profit and Loss Statement from 30+ minutes to seconds.
 - The creation of other reports experienced similar gains in processing time.
 - The creation of detailed and customized reports, otherwise unavailable from the AS/400's accounting software package.
 - Prior to leaving, I was developing a modest data warehouse for the Accounting department and plant's use.

Other Projects

• GitHub: https://github.com/brian-sigurdson

• Personal: <u>www.bks.name</u>

WORK HISTORY

Staff Accountant Oldcastle Perrysburg, Perrysburg OH 1995-2006

• In additional to normal departmental duties, I designed, developed, and maintain an intranet website for the Accounting department using: Java, Linux, JEE/J2EE (JSP, Servlets, EJB), PostgreSQL and MySQL databases, JBoss, Tomcat, Apache POI, and Eclipse.

Registered Representative Trainee Olde Discount Stockbrokers, Detroit MI

1995-1995

Prospected for potential clients while preparing for licensing exams.

Accounting Analyst Dana Commercial Credit, Maumee OH 1994-1995

• In addition to normal accounting duties, I assisted in transferring the department to a new lease accounting software package.